Okay, let's get started. So, the first
thing it asks us to do is to write a
program that takes four inputs. Each
input should be a letter grade. So,
we'll just say let letter grade one
equal
um prompt.
What was your letter grade or class one?
And I'll put a semicolon. If you want to
quickly copy lines of code, you can hold
the option key and the shift key and
push the down arrow. So that's two,
three, four. If you want to rapidly edit
multiple lines of code, you can click
and then hold the option or the alt key.
Option if you're on a Windows, alt if
sorry, option if you're on a Mac, alt if
you're on a Windows, and you can click
in two locations. And so I'm going to
change this to letter grade two. Well,
you can click in as many locations as
you want. and it'll put your cursor in
both spots. Letter grade three. Again,
that's alt if you're on a Windows,
option if you're on a Mac. That's four.
Okay, so that's letter grade 1 2 3 and
four. Now, we need to convert each
letter grade to its corresponding grade
point value. U entering an A should
display 4.0 and A minus should display
3.7. So, let's do that. Um let's do it
first for letter grade one. So we'll say
if
um I'm actually going to create um three
four GPA. So we're going to say let GPA
one
zero. And then we'll hold option shift
and create four of those.
Make that two three and four. So, what
we're going to do is we're going to say
if
letter grade one is
an A,
then we want to set GPA 1
to be 4.0.
else. If letter grade one
is an A minus,
then we want to set GPA 1 to 3.7.
And I'm going to copy this table up
so that I can reference it as I'm making
this conversion.
I'm going to highlight the lines that
I'm going to be using over and over. So,
and then I'm going to hold option shift
down. Oh, looks like I highlighted a
little too much. So, let's
move that onto its own line. Highlight
option shift down. So, there's uh one L
if two L if three L ifs. So it'll be a a
minus
b plus
um
b
minus c plus c c minus
d + d
minus and then we'll put the else
statement here x um
and here we'll set the GPA one to
whatever F is. F is 0.0. Z. So,
okay. So, A is 4.0.
A minus is 3.7,
B+
is 3.3,
B is 3.0,
B minus is
2.7.
C++
should be
2.3.
C should be 2.0.
And if you want to fast forward the um
you can. I'm just going to keep putting
in these grades. C minus 1.7
D+ is 1.3.
All right.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
save that
and then I'm going to test it. So, I'm
going to say alert GPA 1. So, I'm going
to save
and
go visit my website.
And was your letter grade? Let's put in
a B+.
B+ B plus B plus 3.3. So let's go over
make sure 3.3 was what we wanted. 3.3 B+
GPA 3.3. And that is correct. So we know
this if statement works.
All right. Well, now we just have to do
this four more times. So, what we're
going to do is we're going to
highlight all this, copy it,
paste it,
hold the option key, and click
everywhere where there was a one. We're
going to change it to a two.
Okay. And we're going to do that again
for three.
If you're wondering, it was intentional.
This is really repetitive so that you
appreciate that you don't have to do
this once you know how to do a little
more advanced programming.
If you're someone who uses AI, this
would be a wonderful time
to put this into your favorite AI tool
and ask it to do this for you.
Okay. And one more time for four.
If you noticed, our code is getting
really, really long and long code is
harder to maintain. Um,
so when you learn how to use functions
and loops, this will be a lot faster and
a lot less lines of code.
Okay.
So, we'll save that. Now, we have
converted each letter to a GPA. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to say
convert letter grade one. Then I'm going
to come to the end of that. Put a
comment here and say convert letter
grade two.
Come to the end of that
vert letter grade three.
Come to the end of that.
Convert letter grade four.
Okay.
So, it says um take inputs, convert them
to their grade point value. Um there's
the table and then I'll convert once
we're done converting. We're going to
assume they're all worth three credits
and we want to take the four grade
points and calculate a GPA or grade
point average. So, we'll say let total
GPA equal um to get an average you sum
them and then divide them by the number
of numbers. So, we're going to say GPA 1
plus GPA 2 plus GPA 3 plus GPA 4 / 4.
And that should give us the total GPA.
After calculating the GPA, display one
of these exact messages and then it has
each of those messages. So, we're going
to say if total GPA is 3.3 or higher, so
we'll say greater than or equal to 3.3.
Then, we want to alert
your GPA is GPA. Great job. Your
consistent efforts are paying off. Keep
challenging yourself. And since we're
inputting the GPA, I'm going to use the
back tick that's under the escape key.
Paste that in. Um,
and where it says GPA, I'm going to put
dollar sign, uh, curly braces, and I'm
going to put total GPA. Great job. Your
consistent efforts are paying off. Keep
challenging yourself and building on
this progress. So, cool. And then I'm
going to say else if total GPA is
greater than or equal to um 2.3.
And you may be wondering why I didn't
use an and to make sure it's between 2.3
and 3.3. The reason is that code
executes from the top to the bottom. So
your if statement executes first, which
means if you get to this else if
statement, you already know that your
GPA was not higher than 3.3. So this was
a little bit of a trick. Um here um you
don't actually have to use an and but I
wrote it so that you might want to. Um,
you could use an and, but it won't do
anything here because you've already
removed the chance that it could be
higher than 3.3 before you get to this
else if and then now we'll alert
the next message. Um,
paste that in.
And here we'll do dollar sign curly
braces and we'll put total GPA.
And then if it's 2.3 or below, display
that message. And we're just going to
say else
alert.
And it looks like this one also has our
GPA inside of the string. So we'll use a
back tick.
and we'll close it.
All right. And if we've done this
correctly, it should work. So, let's
shoot for an above 3.3 GPA. Um so we'll
come over to our um running website and
it says what is the letter grade for
class one or who
reload the website.
What is your letter grade for class one?
A a
and a your GPA is four points. Um it
didn't have the 0.0 but great job. Your
consistent effort is paying off. Keep
challenging yourself and building on
this progress. Let's reload um and look
at our code. So, we want to have a GPA
between 2.3 and 3.3. And if we look
here, so if we put in all B's, that
should trigger that message. So, B, B,
B, and B. Congratulations 3.0. Making
steady progress. Um, and then to test
the last one, we'll put in D minus, D
minus, D minus, and D minus. And we get
our GPA is 0.7. Um, and we got our last
message. And that should complete this
video.